now sometimes you may need to find
the absolute value of
a complex number
what is the absolute value of 3
plus 4i
here's the equation
the absolute value of a plus bi
is equal to the square root
of a squared plus b squared
it's just the way it works out
so this is going to be the square root
of 3 squared plus 4
squared three squared is nine
four squared is sixteen
and the square root of well nine plus
sixteen is twenty-five
and the square root of twenty-five is
five
so that's the absolute value of three
plus four
so now it's your turn
calculate the absolute value of
minus 12i
so this is going to be the square root
of 5 squared
plus the square root of negative 12
squared which you could just write 12
squared
5 squared is 25
12 times 12 is 144
and these two add up to 169. the square
root of 169 is
13.
and so that's the absolute value of 5
minus 12i
so now why is the absolute value of 3
plus 4i
equal to 5
one way i like to think about it is this
if we plot 3 plus 4i
we need to travel 3 units on the x-axis
and up 4 on the y-axis
so here it is
now let's turn it into a triangle
so this portion of the triangle is three
this part is four
and
let's find the missing side this is a
this is b
the hypotenuse is c we know that a
squared plus b squared is equal to c
squared
so c is simply the square root
of a squared plus b squared
and it turns out that the absolute value
is basically the hypotenuse of the
triangle
which is five
so it helps to know the special
triangles like 3 4 5
5 12 13. notice the answer for the
second example was 13.
there's also the 7 24 25 triangle
and the 8 15 17 triangle
you